I'm David Copperfield
And you're about to see
a whole lotta of magic
For me, watching this
retrospective is like looking thru
A high school yearbook
It's got some of my best illusions
Some of the worst
haircuts ever put on film
And clothing choices that kept
the '70s alive
At the end, we've added
some recent pieces,
Created for our Broadway show
So sit back and take a look
at 15 years of magic
Well, actually, 20 years of magic
I started very young
David
Okay, go
I dunno where to begin
I've been doing magic all my life
I love magic. I love magic
That's intimate
but I also love magic
That's spectacular, like the year
I decided to vanish a train
I had taken a ride
with the Orient Express
And I knew I had to do
something with it
Well, it took me a year
to find a train car
And a year to work out
the illusion
A train car from the Orient
Express
It weights 70 tons
That's 140,000 pounds
It's 85 feet of steel and iron
A million dollars was spent
just to restore it
A train on its tracks
Set on a floor of solid concrete
A group of spectators will
surround the train
Holding hands forming a circle
around it
Our camera this shot will never
cut away
No camera edits, no video effects
You'll see it at home just like
you'd see it
If you were here with me
Take a good look
'Cause in a few seconds the train
we're in right now
Hopefully won't be here anymore
Everybody, pick up your ropes
Cover cloth
Keep your hands together
There are no camera tricks?
No. All the magic is done live
What you see at home is exactly
What you'd see if you were there
with a live audience
And what's the most dangerous
thing you've ever done?
See these spikes?
For a year
I practiced hanging up side down
Bound and strapped from ropes
10 stories in the air
Then we set the ropes on fire
I had two minutes to escape
before the ropes burned thru
But on the night of the T.V.
Special
To make it a bit more interesting,
We added these spikes beneath me
I was up there in the air
And I looked down on the spikes
And that really freaked me out
I didn't wanna just do an escape
I wanna combine it with the
ritualistic challenges that took
In the jungles of African and
the Amazon
Ceremonially tests of commitment
Courage
They'll hoist me 10 stories above
the spikes
I remember looking down
And the thought of falling on them
Didn't make me very happy
I didn't wanna die that way
Don't try this at home
I hate these spikes
I do 500 show a year
And people think I'm crazy
But I really love it
What I Love the most is
interacting with the audience
You never know what to expect
It's different every night
And the weirdest thing can happen
Thank you very, very much
You know, something really weird
has been happening to me
I keep getting these premonitions
You know when you think of
something and then
It comes true later on?
Well, I've been able to predict
graffiti
Yeah, where it's gonna happen
When it's gonna happen
And what it's gonna say
In fact, I brought with me a...
Brick wall tonight
I got it from East Berlin
They weren't using it anymore
And I've made a prediction inside
This envelope here
It's on a big piece of paper
It's a big drawing that
I made before
The show. Actually it's a painting
It's got some numbers,
some colors a picture
I'm not gonna show it to
you just yet
I'm gonna leave it sealed
inside the envelope
I'm gonna hang it from this
lamp right here
And I'm not gonna touch it
I do need to borrow a lady
from the audience
And I'm gonna do that by throwing
these bricks
Maybe I should just get her myself
What's your name?
Tiffany.
Big hand for Tiffany
Have we ever met before?
No
No. We're gonna try to find some
other people
We've never met before We're
gonna do that with this brick
It's a rubber brick, so don't
worry it's gonna come right at you
Tiffany, you're gonna throw it
into the audience
When I tell you to Turn your back
to the audience
If it comes close to you, catch it
I need a guy to catch this brick
So show what a man you really are
Tiffany, whip it good. Go for it
Go for it?
Yep
Incredible distance there
You, sir
What is your favorite wild animal?
Not your wife
A tiger
A tiger, fine
Tiffany
Shake up these cans of paint
Shake them up real good
Sir, what's your favorite color?
Yellow
What's your favorite color, sir?
Good choice
Come with me, Tiffany
A blue tiger, Tiffany
Above this line
Stand up here
Stand right up here
Here, I'll take that
Stand right up there
And draw a blue tiger
Charles Darwin would be proud
Take that brick and throw it
behind you as far as you can
Whip it good
Nearest adult guy
Gentleman with the beard
What are your initials?
D.G.
D.G. What's your favorite color?
Red
Great. Red D.G.
Hold on to this, Tiffany.
Come with me
I do the easy ones
D.G., where are you?
Yes. What's your phone number?
Just the first three digits
661 . OK.
Now the last four digits
Take that brick throw it
behind you as far as you can
Whip it good
Nearest adult guy. Who is got it?
You, sir, what's your name?
I'm sorry?
Richard
Richard?
What?
Richard
How do you spell that?
R-I-C-H-A-R-D
Richard
Tiffany, how are you?
Richard, the man next to you
in the glasses.
What's your name?
Harvey
Shouldn’t it be...Harvay?
Richard
Just a joke, Richard
Who is the lady nearest to you?
Judy
He's nodding his head yes
I hope you've got call waiting
Maybe it's because of the
spray paint
Put them on that table
And wait for me over there
Tiger man, where are you?
Where is the tiger man?
There you are
Now, we didn't prearrange this,
did we?
No, we didn't
Tiffany, have we ever met before?
No
D.G., where are you?
Raise your hand
Dick, Harvey, Judy, I mean,
Richard
Have we met before? In unison
No
Look up unison
Come over here
Stand right over here
This envelope has been hanging
In full view the entire time
I haven't touched it
If the picture I made before
the show
Matches the picture we made
That will be a miracle
Tiffany, hold on to this corner
right there. Hold it up high
A blue tiger. Check it out
Does this not impress you?
It's even new
Hold on that corner there.
Hold it up
Hold it up nice and high. D.G.
661 -9737
You chose the color red.
Check it out
And Dick Loves Judy
Sorry, Harvey
This place is amazing
It's filled with magical mystery
What do you mean?
Look inside that trunk
That's Houdini's trunk
When I got it I looked inside
And I found a piece of paper
With Houdini's own instructions
On how he was gonna do the
illusion that night
It's a classic
Of magic called Metamorphosis
Houdini would tie up his wife,
Bess
Lock her inside the trunk
And very quickly they changed
places
I've always wanna do an illusion
like that
It's taken me 1 4 years to find
a way
To make my own
When I look back over the past
15 years
I realize I spent most of that
time creating new illusions
I grew up in New Jersey
My mom was in insurance
My dad owned a men's clothing
store
Before I was in my teens
I thought it would be cool to
become a ventriloquist
It turned out this place that sold
props for ventriloquist
Is also a magic shop
So instead walking out with
a new dummy
I ended up with a bag of tricks
I started doing little shows
in my home town
When I was 1 8, I got this part
In a musical called
''The Magic Man''
I got to do my own illusions
and sing
And the longer the play ran the
more illusions I performed
And the less songs they wanted me
to do
So I guess I wasn't cut out to
be a singer
When the show closed
I starved in New York for a year
And my dad would slip me a few
bucks to pay the heating bill
I sat in my apartment, inventing
magic finding the right music
And staging the routines
I knocked on a lotta doors
And sent out a lotta videotapes
One day I got a phone call to
host a T.V. Show
I was 19 and I couldn’t believe it
My first few specials were to
music by Gershwin
My inspirations were Gene Kelly
and Fred Astaire
I thought I was really cool
I wore big collars, shiny jackets
and a bad haircut
On my fourth special, I wanna
go beyond
What had been done before
So I took that shiny jacket
And that bad haircut
And made an airplane disappear
A seven ton jet aircraft
Surrounded by scaffolding
12 feet high
This runway is a solid karmlock
base
The plane can't go down,
can't go up
This switch controls the lights
at the back of the enclosure
When the translucent front
wall is up
The lights will back up the plane,
Casting its silhouette on the wall
So you can see the plane
Right up to the moment it vanishes
The plane is locked into place
It will be surrounded by a
human chain
50 spectators linked together
The spectators are being
blindfolded
To protect the secret of
the illusion
Hold hands till I say let go
Let's do it
This shot won't cut away
You'll see it as if you were there
With absolutely no camera tricks
If you can hear me,
raise your hand
Now
Take your blinds off. We did it
I couldn’t believe it
If I had been sitting at home
I could think of some way
to get outta it
But I was right here,
and there was
No way that plane could’ve left
It's just amazing
What happened to the airplane?
I dunno. It went
It went
Thrilling, it was shocking
You had chills
What did you think when you
when they...they drop it
And you took down your blindfold
and it was gone?
It's emphatical
We put together a brand new
illusion
We're auctioning off a brand
new illusion
The pieces I'm most proud of
The Airplane. The Train
The Flying. The Great Wall
The Burning Rope Escape
And one other is the Death Saw
Give me an example of how you
try to make your magic different
Well, there's a sensual side
to magic
That hadn't really been touched
To me, it wasn't just about
doing tricks
It was about taking the audience
to another place
A special place so they could
really suspend their disbelief
It was about relationships
Moving the audience as well as
amazing them
It was about sharing a feeling
Sometimes romantic,
sometimes funny
Sometimes grand and spectacular
Sometimes daring
And sometimes sensual
Dave
When the audience applauds
like that
You have to say something, like...
Very endearing back to them. OK
Repeat after me.
I have never felt...
Never felt
OK, a little softer now
I have never felt...
So, so much Love
So much Love
In one room before
You're a regular Wayne Newton...
Dave
It's very good
You Love your audience.
I like that
The Statue Of Liberty
Standing 305 feet high
And weighing 450,000 pounds
I was gonna make her disappear
We constructed two scaffolding
towers on Liberty Island
In front of the statue
And had a helicopter to give an
aerial view of the illusion
The audience on Liberty Island
was seated here
200 feet in front of the statue
A circle of lights surrounds the
statue and shines upon it
A curtain would be raised between
the towers
To hide the statue from view
If I successfully vanish
the statue
Searchlights would pass thru
the empty space
That was occupied just moments
before
We even had radar to show the
statue's position
In front of a live audience on
Liberty Island
The disappearance of The Statue
Of Liberty
There's that jacket again
Right about now I'm thinking
I hope this works
Entire thing. It just disappeared
What happened, where it was gone
I have no idea
No idea where it went to
It was fascinating to watch it
I tell you. If I was home
watching T.V
I'd be a little skeptical
But I was here.
I knew it was there
Now it's not there
I dunno what happened to it
When that curtain went down
And there was nothing there
I just couldn’t believe it
Your reaction?
I was amazed
I don't see it
It was there and
it's not there anymore
I've never seen a Statue
Of Liberty
disappear the way this one did
And as the audience watched
I brought her back
So David, what surprises you?
Well, I spend months of time
And energy working
on these huge illusions,
But sometimes it's
the small stuff,
The pure slight of hand
the audience really relates to
I need to borrow a gentleman
from the audience
Let me see what I can find here
Yeah, really
Oh, boy!
He can make the Statue of
Liberty disappear
But he can't walk down a
set of steps
As pulling a rabbit outta hat
But I always try to remember
my partner on stage
Could also be a romantic partner
What about the people you
work with?
It's weird, but the culture of my
craft is sometimes strange
For centuries, magicians have been
taking their assistants
And sticking swords thru them
or cutting them in half
It's as much a part of magic
history
Right now we're gonna do
something really cool
You and I are gonna do it together
So far you've been watching David
do magic before a live audience
Now it's your turn to participate
In a moment, all you have to do is
simply touch your T.V. Screen
As unbelievable as it sounds
David will try to make the magic
happen
Right in your own home
That's right.
Tonight you've seen me choose
people from the audience.
Now I'm choosing you
It's important because if you
don't play along
In the next few minutes,
it'll be totally meaningless
Here's the plan
If there are several of you
in the room
Choose one person to participate
Right now stand up and come
close to your T.V.
Close enough to actually touch
your screen
Do it now and touch my finger
That wasn't the cool part
You can let go off the screen now
But don't move away because in a
moment by touching the screen
You and I are gonna do something
really amazing
Now take a good look at these
destinations of flight
And listen carefully
Here's the idea.
Tonight you're gonna put your
finger here
And fly from place to place
around the circle
And I'm gonna find you
The amazing thing is even though
you're at home and I'm here
I'll know exactly where you are
There are many places to fly to
A star, the clouds, a moon and
so on
I want you to think a secret
number
Between 5 and 15
Any number between 5 and 15
It's your choice
I have no idea what number
you're thinking of
In a moment you're gonna move
your finger the same number
Of times as your secret number
For example, if your secret
number was nine,
You'd move nine times
1 , 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8, 9,
Bringing you to the island.
If it were 6
1 , 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
There are a lotta possibilities
This is your last chance to
participate
So come real close to
your T.V. So you can touch it
Stand over here so everyone
can see
Right now put your finger here
And get ready to move the amount
equal to your secret number
Move as I count. Ready?
1 , 2, 3, 4, 5,
And so on
When you reach your secret number
Stop and keep your finger there
Good
Now get ready to move
in the other direction
The same number you just moved
The amount equivalent to
your secret number
Move in this direction as I count
Ready?
1 , 2, 3, 4,
5, so on
When you finish leave
your finger on the final place
You've touched
Now I know you're not
on the rainbow
So we'll take it away
And I know you're not
in the castle
So I remove it
I know you're not in the mountains
So I take that away
And I know you're not
in the pyramids either,
So I move them, too
In a moment I'll ask you
to move four times
Either in this direction
or that direction
Whichever direction you want
Move four times. Ready?
1 , 2, 3, 4,
And keep your finger there
I know you're not
In the Eiffel Tower
Now I know you're not
In the clouds
And I know you're not
In the city either
Keep your finger touching
the screen
I'm gonna take this arrow
and put it right
Here
Remember you chose your own
secret number
And you flew at random around
the screen
But believe it or not even though
you're at home and I'm here
I'm gonna find you
Keep touching and watch
You're on the moon
Now comes the part of the show
Where I get somebody outta the
audience
And make them into a magician
Sit back
Relax
Shut that kid up
I'm just kidding
Shut him up
You've done so many different
things
Where do you get your ideas?
My library when I look thru
magical history
The recurring theme is
for people to pass thru objects
Or walk thru walls
A friend of mine suggested that
If you're gonna walk thru a wall
Why not
Walk thru The Great Wall of China
I think she was joking but...
I took her seriously
The Great Wall of China
3,000 miles long
The only man made object visible
from the moon
Built to keep armies
from getting thru
Well, I was determined
to walk thru it
This remote control camera
will never cut away
It'll start on one side
of the wall
See me enter the wall
Without cutting away
The camera will travel over
the wall and hopefully
See me emerge from the other side
Walking thru The Great Wall
of China
They even monitored my heart
I've read somewhere that magic
sometimes is based on misdirection
What does that mean?
I'll give you an example
One year I told the powers that
I wanna do a version of...
buried alive
Where I'd be locked into
a container
Covered with tons of earth
And I have to make my escape
Well, they hated the idea
They thought it was morbid
They wanna have nothing to do
with it
So I took the same idea and
put it into a bulling
That was about to implode
You know explode?
And they loved it
I don't think they ever
realized that
It was the same idea
That they said no to
in the first place
That's misdirection
In a few hours
The same thing will be happening
To that bulling behind me
The only difference is
I'll be inside
Locked in a safe, trying to escape
This is a sheet of polished
stainless steel
It's one inch thick
It'll play a very important part
in what we're about to do
I'll have 2 minutes and 30 seconds
To free myself from the safe
Inside the building
And get to this X
That we're placing
on the steel plate
From inside the building to this X
Before the building blows up
We're inside the building
Which is competed wired
with explosives
This safe was provided by
The First Security Safe
The walls are 4 inches thick
We've installed a remote
control camera
So that you at home
And the people outside
Can keep an eye on the safe
at all times
How you doing?
The committee outside is checking
once again to make sure
That the steel plate is solid
And that the X is in place
This timer controls the detonation
of the explosives
It'll count down to 2 minutes and
30 seconds
And then you know what
These officers are here
To ensure everything is on the up
and up
Gentlemen, you examined the safe?
Yes, we have
And you searched me thoroughly?
Yes, we did
Thank you very much
Just keep in mind that
Our T.V. Audience and
our live audience
Are seeing the exact same thing
You at home will see what the
people are seeing right here
We'll simultaneously show our
remote
Controlled camera outside the safe
And our handheld camera
So you'll see everything
Gentlemen?
Guys, just one minute
I always wanna fly on stage
Not just float but really fly live
Right in front of people
Without wings, strings,
or camera tricks
Well, it took 7 years
to finally live that dream
And to make it really believable
I wanted people from the
audience on stage with me
Hello, you come with me, please
Stand over here
This gentleman right here,
come with me
Stand right over here
You can keep going back stage
What, what's your name?
Bambi
I'm sorry?
Your name is Bambi?
Are you serious?
I'm serious
And you must be thumper
Yes. Fine
Bambi, your name is really Bambi?
Yeah
I like that. It's fun to say
See,
I'm in this big Plexiglas box
Picture it solid gold on the back
you can examine the backside
Mitch, you examine the front
I do wanna go home
with some of these props
Examine this side, go for it
You sure you're not thumper?
Come over here
I want you to examine the lid
Yeah, me, too
This is the lid of the box
Make sure it's solid
Nice, nice and strong. Lift it up
Over your head
I'm just kidding come over here
Have a seat right here
Mitch
Bambi, you too
Before you do I'm just curious
Have you ever had any dreams
Where you fly?
No
Perfect. Good
Have a seat right here, Bambi
Even when you were a kid you
never dreamed you could fly?
When you were a little kid. Good
Mitch, your job
Is to keep an eye on this
Plexiglas box
Make sure nobody tampers with it,
OK?
Bambi
Your job is to keep an eye
on Mitch
Make sure he doesn't break the box
Our committee from the audience is
sitting behind the curtain? Good
Did you ever just sit around
and dream?
I do all the time
When I was a kid I didn't think
I fit in at all
I was an only child and I lived
in these apartments where
There weren't any other kids
my own age
So I'd sit outside by myself
And I'd dream
So I wouldn’t feel so alone
You know my best dream?
My best dream was to fly
Not in a balloon or an airplane
But to push against the air
Ride the wind and fly
You ever fly in your dreams?
Even today when I feel lonely
Or insecure, I go back to
that dream
And it helps me leave my problems
and insecurities behind
All the answers were up there
Well, a lotta people have dreams
and
They don't do anything about them
Sometimes I'm afraid that's gonna
happen to me
See
I've been trying to fly for
a long time
I guess if like I was trying
I haven't lost
That was great. I was gonna...
This way
A lotta people think of me in
terms of grand illusion
But in my opinion the most
powerful magic happens
In the performer's hands
It's the purest form of the art
So now take a look at a light
of hand sequence
That features a little tribute
to my first magical influence
I want to...
Show you a home movie
That's me
And that's my grandfather
He's the first person to ever
teach me magic
I was about 10 years old and
He taught me a card trick with
4 aces
And the aces would appear and
disappear it was really cool
And since I was 10 years old
It took me many months to
master it
After I did
I showed it to everybody and
I decided to make magic my life
Everybody thought I was crazy
Except my grandfather
Who always gave me encouragement
I promised him if I ever had
any success
That I'd do his card trick
in my show
Well, my grandfather passed away
Before I ever did a big show
But grandpa...
If you're listening
Tonight I'm gonna keep my promise
Ghosts used to be a standard
theme in magic theater
Illusionists loved the idea of
invoking the other side
Personally I was never big on it
I never got into ghost stories
as a kid
I thought it was weird
And caspers really creeped me out
Way too friendly
Then I heard about an old house
of ill repute
Said to be haunted by the ghosts
of the ladies
Who made it infamous
I need some people from the
audience to verify
What we're about to do
Two guys and a girl
One of the guys needs to be
wearing a jacket that I can borrow
And the girl needs to be
wearing...
Clothes
I'm gonna show you an old newsreel
Back in 1927, the old Barkley
House
Was sold at auction to a stranger
A lady from out of state
Soon the whole town realized the
house became home to a number
Of working girls who were
Entertaining gentlemen callers
in the evening
Barkley House became the local
scandal
And none of the townsfolk ever
spoke it
Except to curse it
As if their dreams came true
A storm swept thru the state
And lightening struck the Barkley
House
And the house
And all the ladies of the night
Perished in the fire
All that was left was one piece
of the structure
The upper room somehow escaped
the destruction
I was able to get the remains
of that room
And reconstruct it here on stage
with us tonight
Just so we could see if anything
else...
Survived
We took the actual wood from the
Barkley House and built a room
That couId be opened and closed
for examination
And that's just what we're about
to do
Our folks in the audience step
right over here
What's your name?
I'm sorry Daniele
Daniele, come with me
I want you to examine the inside
In New York, this would be
a one bedroom
Right this way. I want you
To check out the inside make sure
There's nothing tricky about it
Just a bunch of walls that open
and close and nothing more. OK?
All right gentlemen step right
over here
This gentleman would you mind
standing over here?
The other gentleman can I borrow
your jacket please
If you could examine these ropes
If there's anything in this jacket
You'd like to keep
Now is the time to take it out
You see, there are no material
object
In the spirit world
So we have to provide the spirits
with objects
So they can show their presence
The jacket, these newspapers
A bell, some personal items
Some very personal items
All these things get placed
inside our empty room
Are the ropes OK?
Excellent. Good
I want you to hold on to these two
You take these two and
You're gonna tie them around
my wrists
The ends go around my wrists
Very tight with a double knot
Very, very good
Yes, yes, yes
You take this
And you take this and cross
behind me, please
Tie them in double knot very
tight on my back
Yes, that's tight
Tonight, I'm gonna be the medium
The go-Between between the spirit
world and our world
So if anything should take place
inside our room,
I want you to be sure it's the
spirits
And not me using any trickery
It's important that I can't move
The ropes go around my neck
I want you to tie them very tight
around my neck, in a double knot
Not quite as tight as you tied
around my wrists
This is the Madonna starter kit
You examined the room?
Is it free of any trickery? Fine
Why don't you stand over there
And gentlemen join me inside
the room
I want you to step up here
They're gonna hang you some ropes
Take those ropes and tie my ankles
to the bottom of the chair
The ropes go around my ankles and
the chair
With a double knot at the bottom
As quickly as you can, two knots
And after you've done that
Check the knots in my back and
my neck
Make sure they're still secure
And once you're satisfied stand
outside the room
So you can see around the sides
and behind
Making it impossible for anyone
to enter or leave the room
No self-Respecting spirit would
show themselves in the light
So we're gonna create a little
darkness with this curtain
And see if we can make the spirits
Manifest themselves inside
the room
Our next demonstration we're gonna
use a gentleman’s jacket
And show you something
You will not believe
Spirits, spirits
Take the coat
Gentlemen, step inside.
Check my arms
Are actually thru the sleeves
Ropes tied tightly at the wrists
Ropes extending out the back
Tied in a double knot
Thank you very much
Ladies, it's time
Spirits. Spirits
Remove the coat
Now is the time we invite someone
to join me inside the room
What's your name?
Jonathan
Come over here Jonathan and
have a seat
We’ don’t want you to be scared
so we're gonna blindfold you
Take your left hand and put it
on my shoulder
And your right hand on my arm
That's not my arm
May be I should be the one
that's scared
Once again we'll try to make
the spirits manifest themselves
Inside the room
What happened to your pants?
What happened to your shoes?
Nice pumps, John
Give Jonathan a big round
of applause
Cut me loose
Everybody step down here
Check the ropes in my back
Make sure they're nice and tight
Make sure the knots are still
firmly in place
Then cut me free, please
Take the scissors and
cut the ropes
Right thru, please
Gentlemen, I need you to check
the knots around my wrists
You're enjoying this too much
I'm just kidding
Everybody give our gentlemen
A big
Round of applause
I need you to stand over there
And both of you to step over there
Make sure nothing enters or
leaves that room
Our next experiment is very
strange
We found that if you close the
doors to the empty room
And listen carefully
You can hear sounds from inside
Very strange sounds
It's as if the ladies of the house
aren't aware that they're dead
Their spirits have been trapped
inside all these years
Now they're crying to be free
Let me show you what I mean
Shall we?
Everyone be still
No
Open it
Open it now
Open the back
Need all of you to come down,
please
Step down here. Exactly
Because now's the time I invite
all of you to join me
Inside the room
You look really thrilled about
this whole thing
This is for you. Step right inside
This is a blindfold for you.
Step inside
And this is a parting gift for you
Step right inside
Once you're inside put on your
blindfolds, please
Because we're gonna add one more
element
These curtains were taken from
the house before the fire
They're an item the spirits are
familiar with
We're gonna use them to enclose
ourselves inside the room
Hold up your hands.
We're gonna hand you the curtains.
Very good
We're gonna lift the curtains
and try to arouse the spirits
Lift the curtains
A few years ago
I realized a lifelong dream
I got to appear on Broadway
in my own show,
''Dreams and Nightmares''
Francis Ford Coppola was our
collaborator
Working with him was another
dream come true
Although he wanted me to stuff
my cheeks with cotton
And speak with a Sicilian accent
The illusions were based on my
own dreams and nightmares
We decided to end it with a
sequence that involved
A strong childhood memory
And so from the ending of
the Broadway show
Take a look at a dream
within a dream
You've been terrific
I got one last thing
I'd like to show you
I hope you like it
I hope it works
It's kinda cool
That's it
Maybe this side of the audience
will like it better
Thank you
You see I never saw snow
when I was a kid
I mean I saw it on T.V.
And in the movies
But I never saw snow for myself
When I was a little kid
I grew up in New Jersey but
every winter, my parents and
I would drive to Florida to
visit my aunt
I never got a chance to really
experience winter
Or snow for myself when
I was growing up
When I was about 8 years old
I begged my mom and dad to stay
in New Jersey for the winter
Just so I could see snow for
the first time
And they agreed
And that was the year there
was no snow
Everyday I'd pray for it to snow
No snow
I'd sit outside waiting
for it to snow
It got closer and closer
to Christmas
Still no snow
On Christmas Eve I was up
in my window still in my room
Praying for it to snow
And I fell asleep at the window
My father came and carried me
to bed
A few hours later in the middle
of the night
There was a knock
on my bedroom door
It was my mother
She said, David wake up
And I woke up
She said, David look out
the window
I looked out the window
And it was snowing
I couldn’t believe it
And I ran outside
And I laughed
And I cried
As the snow hit my face and
my hands
That was the first magic
I ever saw
When spring came and
the snow stopped
I cut up little pieces of paper
And threw them in the air
to try to...
Recreate the feeling I felt
When I saw snow for the first time
There was paper all over my house
But it was my way
Of keeping the magic alive
All year long
Even today I realize
How important it is to keep
that sense of wonder
That childlike hope
Knowing if you believe
And you want it enough
Nothing is impossible